A Guide to the Studies of the Virginia Division of Legislative Services, 1978-2000.
Library of Virginia
- Studies (Accession 42271), 1983-1998., Extent: 80 cubic feet (80 boxes)
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Legal and Policy Ramifications of Breast Cancer Susceptibility Gene Research (1995) / Joint Subcommittee Studying Legal and Policy Ramifications of Gene Research (1996) (SJR 372, 1995; SJR 50, 1996), 1995-1996. (Box 22)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, other state laws, correspondence, articles, handouts (No published Senate Document).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Desirability of Allowing the Development of Coal Slurry Pipelines in Virginia (HJR 117, 1983), 1983-1984. (Box 23)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legislative summary, research material, legislation, correspondence, articles, Coal Slurry Pipelines in Virginia: A Preliminary Study by the Virginia Center for Coal and Energy Research at Virginia Tech, 1982 (House Document 27, 1984).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Studying Alternatives for Improving Waste Volume Reduction and Recycling Efforts (The Bottle Bill) (HJR 80, 1988), 1988-1989. (Box 24)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legislative record summary, reports, research material, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles (House Document 60, 1989).
  - State Water Commission (30-187), 1985-1998. (Box 25-30)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts, public hearing comments, audiotapes. Also SJR 264 - Regional Water Authority Study; Lake Gaston Pipeline Compact, 1995; Federal Energy Regulatory Commission applications by Virginia cities for non-project uses of water.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Licensing of Boat Operators and Ways to Enhance Boating Safety (HJR 102, 1990), 1990-1991. (Box 31)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts. House Document 55 (1991).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Use of Jet Skis (SJR 29, 1990), 1990-1991. (Box 31)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles. Senate Document 14 (1991).
  - Subaqueous Minerals and Materials Study Commission (SJR 126, 1985; SJR 85), 1985-1986. (Box 32-33)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, presentations. Also House Chesapeake and Its Tributaries Study; Materials from Royalties Subcommittee.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Effectiveness of the Management Structure of the Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries (HJR 191, 1992), 1992-1993. (Box 34)
    - Agendas, reports, correspondence, audiotapes. House Document 80 (1993) See also House Document 62, 1994.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Necessity for Improvements in Erosion and Sediment Control Programs (HJR 178, 1991), 1991-1992. (Box 35-36)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research material, legislation, correspondence, articles, public hearing comments, handouts, audiotapes. House Document 73 (1992).
  - Joint Subcommittee Assessing the Long-Range Financial Status of the Game Protection Fund (HJR 293, 1991), 1991. (Box 37)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legislative record summary.
  - Select Committee Studying the Game Protection Fund (HJR 444, 1993), 1991-1994. (Box 37)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material. House Document 54 (1991); House Document 90 (1994).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Oil and Gas Drilling under the Chesapeake Bay (HJR 251, 1991), 1991-1992. (Box 37)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, legislation, correspondence. House Document 55 (1992).
  - Blue Ridge Economic Development Commission (HJR 283, 1994), 1994-1996. (Box 38)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, legislation, correspondence, articles, public hearing comments. House Document 66 (1996).
  - House Agriculture Subcommittee C Studying Companion Animals (SB 479 and SB 160, 1992), 1992. (Box 39)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research material, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, presentations, audiotapes.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Solid Waste Policies (HJR 232, 1992), 1992. (Box 40)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations, public hearing comments. Also two maps - An Inventory of State-Owned Lands Along the Atlantic Coast of Accomack and Northampton Counties in the Commonwealth of Virginia.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Pollution Prevention (SJR 103, 1992; SJR 207, 1993), 1992-1994. (Box 41)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, presentations. Senate Document 43 (1993); Senate Document 59 (1994).
  - House Committee on Mining and Mineral Resources Studying Water Supplies Contaminated by Mining Activities (HB 896, 1992), 1992. (Box 42)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, presentations, public hearing comments, audiotapes.
  - Coal and Energy Study Commission - Policies to Promote Greater Use of Wood Processing Industry Wastes for Fuel in State Facilities (HJR 69, 1992), 1992-1993. (Box 43)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, correspondence, presentations. House Document 23 (1993); Senate Document 41 (1993).
  - Combined Sewer Overflow (SJR 198, 1989; SJR 168, 1991), 1989-1992. (Box 43)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, correspondence. Senate Document 40 (1990); Senate Document 30 (1991); Senate Document 28 (1992).
  - Developing Douthat State Park into a Regional, Multi-Purpose Recreational Facility (SJR 54, 1996), 1996-1997. (Box 43)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research materials, correspondence, handouts, audiotapes. Also information from study on expanding recreational facilities (HJR 130, 1988). Senate Document 33 (1997) See also House Document 38 (1989).
  - State Water Commission Study of Small Waterworks (HJR 652, 1993), 1993-1994. (Box 43)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research materials, legislation, correspondence. House Document 96 (1994) [State Water Commission Annual Report].
  - House Committee on Mining and Mineral Resources - Regulation of Underground Injection Wells (HJR 310, 1991), 1991. (Box 43)
    - Agendas, reports, research materials, correspondence.
  - State Water Commission Study of the Application and Enforcement of Water and Wastewater Regulations (HJR 460, 1991), 1991-1993. (Box 43)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, correspondence. House Document 59 (1992); House Document 74 (1993) [State Water Commission Annual Report].
  - State Water Commission Study of Financial Responsibility for Above-Ground Storage Tanks (SJR 114 (1990), 1990-1991. (Box 43)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research materials. House Document 57 (1991) [State Water Commission Annual Report].
  - Enhancing End-Use Recycling Markets (HJR 244, 1992; HJR 466, 1993), 1992-1994. (Box 44-45)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research materials, other state laws, correspondence, presentations, handouts, audiotapes. House Document 95 (1994).
  - Soil and Water Conservation Districts (SJR 18, 1994; SJR 275, 1995), 1994-1996. (Box 46)
    - Minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other state laws, correspondence, presentations, handouts, audiotapes. Senate Document 35 (1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee on Alternative Strategies for Assisting Tobacco Farmers (HJR 224, 1994), 1994-1996. (Box 47)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research materials, correspondence, articles, presentations, handouts. House Document 62 (1994), House Document 67 (1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Review Drinking Water Problems in Southwestern Virginia (HJR 104, 1996), 1996-1998. (Box 48)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations, audiotapes. Also Southwest Virginia Water Symposium, 1996. House Document 3 (1998).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study Long-term Funding Options to Meet the Funding and Operational Needs of the Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries (HJR 552, 1997), 1997-1998. (Box 48)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, research materials, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations, public hearing comments, audiotapes. House Document 86 (1998).
  - Joint Select Committee on the Structural Conditions and Costs of Maintaining Dams Owned by Soil and Water Conservation Districts (HJR 446 / SJR 275, 1997), 1997-1998. (Box 48)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, audiotapes. House Document 49 (1998).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Mine Safety Law of 1966 (HJR 645, 1996), 1993-1994. (Box 49-52)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations, handouts, public hearing comments, audiotapes, survey results. House Document 86 (1994).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Use of Vehicles Powered by Clean Fuels (HJR 113, 1990; HJR 494, 1991; HJR 100, 1992; HJR 9, 1994; HRJ 410, 1995; SJR 334, 1991), 1990-1996. (Box 53-54)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations, handouts. House Document 50 (1991); House Document 47 (1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Sustainable Development (HJR 29, 1994; HJR 536, 1995), 1994-1997. (Box 55-56)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other state laws, articles, handouts, audiotapes. See also Blueprint for Sustainable Development in Virginia, 1994 (Environment Law Institute). House Document 6 (1997).
  - Coal and Energy Commission, 1996-1998. (Box 57)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence, articles, handouts, audiotapes.
  - Solid Waste Disposal, Collection and Recyling Services Provided by Water and Sewer Authorities (HJR 585, 1997), 1997. (Box 58)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, articles, handouts.
  - Chesapeake Bay Partnership Council (Code 9-334), 1995-1996. (Box 59)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legislative record summary, reports, research materials, correspondence, articles, presentations, handouts.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Swine Production (HJR 573, 1997), 1997-1998. (Box 60-61)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legistative record summary, study plans, reports, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations, public hearing comments, handouts.
  - Special Subcommittee - Poultry Waste Management and Chesapeake Bay (HB 1207, 1998), 1997-1998. (Box 61)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legistative record summary, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations, public hearing comments, handouts, audiotapes.
  - Special Subcommitee on Wine and the ABC Commission (SJR 48, 1983), 1983. (Box 62)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, correspondence, articles, public hearing comments, handouts.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying All Terrain Vehicles (SJR 6, 1988), 1988-1989. (Box 62)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, handouts. Senate Document 13 (1989).
  - Commission on Local Government Structures (Grayson Commission) (HJR 163, 1986), 1986-1990. (Box 63)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence, public hearing comments, handouts. House Document 69 (1990).
  - Commission on Population Growth and Development, 1992. (Box 63)
    - Agendas, reports, legislation, correspondence. Reorganizes Dept. of Planning and Budget.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Virginia's System of Taxing Intangible Personal Property (HJR 202, 1992), 1992. (Box 63)
    - Agendas, research materials, legislation, correspondence.
  - Joint Subcommittee on Growth Management (Byrne Commission / Land use / Transferable Development Rights / Impact fees), 1991. (Box 63)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles, handouts.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Staffing and Funding of Officers of Locally Elected Constitutional Offices (HJR 105, 1992), 1986-1990. (Box 64)
    - Correspondence.
  - Joint Subcommittee on Business Location Decisions (HJR 41, 1992; HJR 448, 1991), 1991-1992. (Box 64)
    - Legislations, correspondence.
  - Commission on Oil Spill Readiness (SJR 228, 1991; SJR 60, 1992), 1991-1992. (Box 64)
    - Agendas, correspondence.
  - Study of the Federal Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (HJR 98, 1992), 1992. (Box 64)
    - Correspondence.
  - Commission on Capital Financing Needs of Small Businesses in Virginia (HJR 24, 1992), 1992-1993. (Box 64)
    - Agendas, reports, correspondence. House Document 82 (1993).
  - Governor's Advisory Commission on the Dillon Rule and Local Government (SJR 83, 1992), 1992. (Box 64)
    - Agenda, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, public hearing comments.
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study Uses of Camp Pendleton (HJR 83, 1992), 1992. (Box 64)
    - Agendas, research materials, legislation, correspondence, public hearing comments.
  - Cost Effective Measures Which Enable Virginia to Comply with the Clean Air Act (SJR 104, 1992) 1992-1993. (Box 64)
    - Reports, research materials, corresponcence. Senate Document 21 (1993).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Public Procurement Act and Regulations Adopted by the Division of Purchase and Supply (HJR 106, 1992), 1992-1993. (Box 64)
    - Agendas, reports, research materials, other state laws, legislation, articles, handouts. Also survey responses by insitutions of higher education on how DGS could improve the procurement process. House Document 77 (1993).
  - Southside Economic Development Commission (A.L. Philpott) (HJR 106, 1990; HJR 300, 1991), 1990-1993. (Box 65)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, correspondence. House Document 42 (1991), House Document 45 (1992), House Document 67 (1993).
  - Establishing the Virginia Commission on Oil Spill Readiness (SJR 56, 1990; SJR 228, 1991), 1990-1993. (Box 65)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, correspondence (1990-1993).
  - Blue Ridge Economic Development Commission (HJR 451, 1991; HJR 92, 1992), 1991-1993. (Box 65)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence. House Document 60 (1991), House Document 78 (1993).
  - Reconstituting the Commission on Local Government Structures and Relationships (Grayson Commission) (HJR 456, 1991), 1991. (Box 65)
    - Legislation and correspondence. Mainly information on disbanding the Commission.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Imposition of Local Business License Tax on Non-Profit Hospitals and Universities (HJR 361, 1991), 1991-1993. (Box 65)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence, public hearing comments. House Document 17 (1993).
  - Healthcare for ALL Virginians (SJR 118, 1990), 1990-1991. (Box 65)
    - Research/background materials, correspondence. Senate Document 34 (1991).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Incentives and Obstacles Facing Businesses When Making Virginia Location Decisions in Virginia (HJR 448, 1991), 1991-1992. (Box 66)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legislative records summary, reports, research materials, other state laws, correspondence, handouts. House Document 54 (1992).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study Current and Potential Funding for Public Transportation in Hampton Roads (HJR 656, 1995), 1995-1996. (Box 67)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, presentations, public hearing comments, handouts, audiotapes. House Document 71 (1996).
  - Ad Hoc House General Laws Study of Riverboat Gambling, 1992-1996. (Box 68-69)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles.
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Need for Limitation Periods for Complaints Against Regulants (HJR 703, 1993), 1993-1994. (Box 70)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, legislative summary, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, handouts. House Document 91 (1994).
  - Possibility of Temporarily Switching Workplaces of Public and Private Employees (HJR 205, 1992), 1992-1993. (Box 70)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, correspondence, handouts. House Document 68 (1993).
  - Criteria for Evaluating Sales and Use Tax Exemption Requests (SJR 249, 1993), 1993-1994. (Box 70)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence. Senate Document 61 (1994).
  - Capital Financing Needs of Small Business (HJR 24, 1992), 1992-1993. (Box 70)
    - Reports. House Document 82 (1993).
  - The Interrelationships Between the Powers of the Commonwealth and the Powers of Local Governments in Environmental and Building Code Matters (HJR 519, 1993), 1993-1994. (Box 70)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, articles, handouts. House Document 85 (1994).
  - Feasibility and Effects of Raising the Retirement Allowance and Implications of Removing the Age Requirements for Members of the State Police Officers Retirement System (HJR 625, 1993), 1993-1994. (Box 70)
    - Study plans, reports, correspondence. House Document 66 (1994).
  - Governmental Actions Affecting Private Property Rights (HJR 624, 1993), 1993-1997. (Box 71)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research materials, other state laws, correspondence. House Document 2 (1997).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Privatization of Certain State Government Functions (SJR 142, 1993; SJR 17, 1994), 1993-1995. (Box 71)
    - Study plans, research materials, correspondence. Senate Document 55 (1992).
  - Taxation of Retirement Benefits (SJR 124, 1994), 1994. (Box 71)
    - Reports, research materials, correspondence.
  - VDOT Land Transfer to Shenandoah National Park (SJR 274, 1993), 1993. (Box 71)
    - Reports, research materials, correspondence.
  - Sufficiency and Distribution of Funds in the Transportation Trust Fund (SJR 240, 1993), 1993-1994. (Box 71)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence, presentations. Senate Document 49 (1994).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Local Revenue Resources (HJR 160, 1994), 1994-1995. (Box 71)
    - Agendas, reports, research materials, correspondence. House Document 69 (1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Feasibility of Creating an Independent Budget Office (HJR 650, 1995), 1995. (Box 72)
    - Correspondence.
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study Proffer Zoning (HJR 280, 1994), 1994. (Box 72)
    - Agendas, reports, correspondence. See related House Document 65 (1999).
  - Efficiency and Effectiveness of the Escheats Laws (HJR 592, 1995), 1995-1996. (Box 72)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials. House Document 72 (1996).
  - Taxation of Motor Carrier Equipment (SJR 366, 1995), 1995-1996. (Box 72)
    - Agendas, correspondence. Senate Document 30 (1996).
  - Dulles Airport Regional Economic Development Commission (HJR 176, 1994; HJR 445, 1995), 1994-1996. (Box 72)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence. House Document 21 (1995); House Document 54 (1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Business, Professional and Occupational License Tax (HJR 613, 1995), 1995. (Box 72)
    - Correspondence.
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Business, Professional and Occupational License Tax (HJR 526, 1993), 1993-1994. (Box 72)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials. House Document 78 (1994).
  - Regional Delivery of Governmental Services in the Urban Regions of the Commonwealth (HJR 281, 1994), 1994. (Box 72)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, correspondence.
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study Virginia's Current Bingo and Raffle Statutes (SJR 195, 1993; SJR 12, 1994; SJR 266, 1995), 1993-1995. (Box 73)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, articles, public hearing comments, handouts. Senate Document 63 (1994); Senate Document 57 (1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Abandoned Solid and Hazardous Waste Sites (HJR 193, 1996), 1996-1997. (Box 74)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence. Environmental Risk Assessment (DEQ). House Document 85 (1997).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Abuse and Enforcement Laws Related to Handicapped Parking (HJR 198, 1996; SJR 86, 1996), 1996-1997. (Box 75)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentaions, handouts. Senate Document 21 (1997).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Investigative and Enforcement Tools, Funding Mechanism, Uniform Coverage and Private Right of Action of the Virginia Consumer Protection Act (HJR 143, 1994), 1994-1995. (Box 76)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other state laws, correspondence, articles, audiotapes. House Document 34 (1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Taxation of Motor Carrier Equipment in the Commonwealth (SJR 366, 1995), 1995-1996. (Box 77)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other state laws, legislation, correspondence, handouts. Senate Document 30 (1996).
  - Study of Gross Receipts Tax Imposed on Insurance Companies (HJR 202, 1996), 1996-1997. (Box 77)
    - Minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials. House Document 78 (1997).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study Delivery of Government Services to the Greater Richmond Area (SJR 383, 1995; SJR 261, 1996), 1995-1998. (Box 78)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence. Senate Document 32 (1996); Senate Document 39 (1998).
  - Commission on State and Local Government Taxing Authority (HJR 487, 1995), 1995-1996. (Box 78)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans, reports, research materials, correspondence, presentations. House Document 62 (1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Business, Professional and Occupational License Tax (HJR 110, 1994), 1994-1995. (Box 78)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence. House Document 59 (1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study Virginia's Current Bingo and Raffle Statutes (SJR 195, 1993; SJR 12, 1994; SJR 266, 1995), 1993-1995. (Box 79)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, articles, public hearing comments. Senate Document 64 (1994); Senate Document 57 (1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Examine Finance Options for the Purpose of Constructing a Baseball Stadium (HJR 228, 1996; SJR 101, 1996), 1996-1997. (Box 80)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, correspondence, articles, presentations, public hearing comments, handouts. House Document 7 (1997).
- Studies (Accession 42785), 1991-1999., Extent: 9 cubic feet (9 boxes)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Compliance with Military Selective Service Act for State Employment (HJR 194), 1998. (Box 1)
    - Reports, research materials, correspondence, audiotapes.